# Artur Kondas

### Contact

Personal Site: akondas.com

Email: arturkondas@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/arturkondas

### **Profile**

A Senior Software Engineer generalist with over five years of experience spanning from IT Support to teaching and Software Development. Using Belbin's Team Roles, best described as a combination of Plant and Monitor Evaluator; I'm always full of ideas and unconventional approach to problems, but still being able to see all the options and judge accurately. Willing to learn and improve, but at the same time to teach and help others.

Site Reliability Engineering Guild lead & evangelist. Go enthusiast, open source contributor and trainer. Team & tech lead, occasionally an architect. Experienced in DevOps and reliable CI/CD practices. Advocate for asynchronous teamwork and team morale over sticking to pre-fabricated templates. I believe in continuous improvement not only in code, always learning something

Avid fan of remote working and work based on trust, not on numbers. I get stuff done (to put it mildly).

# **Projects**

#### Asynchronous chat

Built a set of highly secure and highly available Go AWS lambdas utilising Amazon Lex & Connect functionality.

## AI-powered analysis & data scraping microservices

Designed and built a microservices suite for data scrapping and analysis. Reworked the POC written by a previous team to decrease the time of discovery from 12 hours to 10 minutes.

### AI-powered crime prevention systems

Built and maintained a set of microservices for video data processing and AI integration.

#### Music video in terminal

Wrote first ever music video in Golang. Did everything apart from singing - wrote, record, mixed, mastered, planned out, wrote the video, released the video.

# Automated my daily chores in terminal

If there's something I've been using to help me with my work/daily chores, 99/100 times I wrote an CLI for this. Blogging? Automated. Switching Git accounts? Automated. Scrapping data to see if the flour I want is available and notifying me over various channels? Automated.

### **Employment**

Barclays (via ECS Digital) / Go Software Engineer October 2020 - Present ECS Digital / Go Software Engineer July 2019 - Present Calipsa / Full Stack Software Engineer

January 2019 - July 2019

/ Scrum Master

March 2019 - July 2019

Sparta Global / Software Development Technical Trainer

September 2018 - January 2019

\_\_\_\_\_

Freelance / Full-Stack Developer

January 2017 - June 2018

ABB / Application Specialist

January 2018 - June 2018

/ IT Support Specialist

March 2017 - December 2017

Capgemini / English Customer Service Advisor

August 2016 - February 2017

#### Skills

Programming Languages Go (Golang, very much preferred), Javascript, C/C#/C++, Python, Ruby

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, dGraph, Neo4J, AWS Suite (RDS, DynamoDB)

Frameworks/Libraries gRPC, React, Vue, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, ffmpeg

Infrastructure Terraform, Ansible, Chef

Cloud & Orchestration AWS, GCP, Kubernetes, RDS, EC2, S3, Docker

CI/CD Jenkins, Puppet, GitHub Actions

Version Control Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Project/Team Management Agile, Scrum, ITIL

Automatic/Static Deployment tools GitHub Pages, Netlify, Heroku

## Education

Cracow University of Technology Power Engineering / BEng

2013 - 2017

Engineering thesis: Acoustic measurements of electrical engines

### Languages

- Polish (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Spanish (Basic)
- French (Basic)

## Certfications

- Site Reliability Engineering Foundation DevOps Institute May 2021
- AWS Certified Database Specialty Amazon March 2021
- Mulesoft Certified Developer Mulesoft January 2021
- AWS Certified Developer Associate Amazon October 2020
- .NET advanced Comarch June 2018
- Excel Intermediate Langolian November 2017
- ITIL Foundation Conlea June 2017

- Oracle SQL Introduction Langolian April 2017
- AutoCAD 2015 Intermediate Cadsoft June 2015

# Open Source / Volunteer

- Speaker Devops Playground
  - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building a ready-to-deploy, CRUD API in Go. Link here
- Speaker Golang in London
  - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building small app to play music from the terminal. Link here
  - Delivered a live-streamed presentation on how to structure small Go programs. Link here
- Guest Speaker ColorInTech
  - Delivered two workshops on annual ColorInTech events
- Contributor Chef
  - Contributed to 5.2.0 #95
- Contributor Grafana Labs
  - Contributed to 7.0.0 beta #22898
- Contributor Rod
  - Contributing to overall functionality of a Chrome Devtools driver in Go
- Contributor / Translator GitHub
  - Translated Unshaky and Rectangle to Polish
- Translator Microsoft
  - Contributed to VS Code translation to Polish
- Technical Trainer Codebar
- Technical Trainer CodeFirst: Girls
  - Delivered two editions of CF:G

### References

References available on request.

#### Disclaimer

Please contact over email prior to phone call, I am not picking up unsolicited calls.

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my offer to be processed for the purposes of recruitment in accordance with the Data Protection Act as of 29 August 1997 (Journal of Acts of 2002, No 101, pos. 926 with later amendments)